Giannis Prekas

Full-Stack Developer





iohnprek@gmail.com



+30 697 60 41 075



Greek



giannis.prekas



A 4-year BSc in Electronic Engineering and 2-year MSc in Networking and Data Communication, 3 years of professional experience in ICT department and more than 8 years in Sales and IT department, constitute my technical and professional background. Whenever I get the chance, I immerse myself in programming, particularly in Python, as a means to continuously refine my skills and stay updated with evolving technologies. My aim is to work in a knowledge driven environment where I can contribute in studying, proposing and designing software solutions, acquire new experiences and propose changes that drive continuous improvement.

Education

MSc in Networking & Data Communications

Kingston University London

09/2013 - 02/2016

BSc in Electronics Engineering

Technological Educational Institute of Piraeus

02/2008 - 05/2012

Experience

Senior Sales Executive & IT Administrator

All Marine International Services Ltd.

07/2015 - Present

- · Researching, identifying and contacting leads
- · Following up and renewing sales
- · Bringing in new business and making sales
- Developing automation tools using Python to enhance sales processes
- Managing network and server infrastructure, ensuring regular data backups.
- · Providing technical support to office computer users

ICT Administrator

10/2012 - 06/2015

Enel Green Power Hellas

- · Oversaw network and server infrastructure, ensuring consistent data backup.
- Provided IT support to both office and remote staff.
- Acted as the first point of contact for IT troubleshooting and issue resolution.
- Managed IT documentation, external support liaisons and staff IT inductions.
- Maintained hardware inventory and software licensing.

Sales

Levi Strauss & Co.

07/2007 - 08/2008

Languages

• Greek (Native)

• English (Professional)

Skills

- Python, Django & Flask
- Selenium
- SOL
- System Administration
- Software Testing

- Linux & Bash
- Git & Github
- REST APIs
- Docker & Kubernetes
- HTML5 & CSS

JavaScript & AJAX

Certifications

Web & Mobile Apps Specialist

UCERT

ITIL v3 Foundation 2011

AXELOS Global Best Practice

07/2023

04/2015

Projects

WizardNotifier

A Python-based application for web content monitoring. Features real-time alerts via Telegram, using Selenium and Telethon for tracking specific web content changes and customizable monitoring settings. Main technologies/libraries used: Python, Selenium, Telethon

SmartHome

Centralized home automation system with a web interface for device interaction. Features include AC, smart plug, temperature monitoring, thermostat management, vacuum, water heater and TV control. Main technologies/libraries used: Python, Django, AJAX, JavaScript, ESPHome, Python-Miio, Tinytuya, Pywebostv, Pysonofflanr3

CopytipBot

Python-based automated betting application for traders. Features include Telegram-integrated betting, customizable user settings, real-time notifications and performance tracking. Supports multiple sports with detailed analysis using Opynepyxl and Pycel.

Main technologies/libraries used: Python, Selenium, Openpyxl, Pycel, Telethon

CopytipValidate

An extension of CopytipBot focused on user verification and real-time alerts. Features include a robust system for authenticating users via names, MAC addresses and UUIDs and Telegram-based notifications for service updates and network issues.

Main technologies/libraries used: Python, Flask

AISParser

A Python-based tool for the maritime industry, designed to automate vessel data extraction from online sources. Key functions include retrieving vessel destination, ETA and status, processing Excel input lists and efficient data export to Excel using Openpyxl.

Main technologies/libraries used: Python, Selenium, Openpyxl

MisParser

A Python tool for the maritime industry, specializing in gathering vessel information from shipping companies. Features include extracting data like vessel name, type, build year and IMO number, handling Excel inputs for data scraping and using Selenium and Beautiful Soup for web scraping. It organizes and exports data to Excel with Openpyxl for easy analysis.

Main technologies/libraries used: Python, Selenium, Openpyxl, Beautiful Soup

BinanceFuturesPythonBot

An automated trading bot for Binance Futures, integrating Python and Telegram via Telethon. Features customizable trading strategies, advanced settings including leverage and position sizing, real-time market data via Binance API and user commands for trade monitoring. Offers multi-platform notifications and tracks trade history and performance in a SQLite database.

Main technologies/libraries used: Python, REST APIs, SQLite, Telethon

• Design and maintenance of the web pages for student registration in the University labs at ATEI Piraeus

Utilized HTML and PHP for interface development, JavaScript for interactive elements and SQL for database management. Responsible for ongoing updates and performance optimization.

Main technologies/libraries used: HTML, PHP, SQL, JavaScript